<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Final Fantasy XIV Network</title>
    <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Final Fantasy XIV Network</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/overview/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Dataset Network Text Analysis Finding Communities Sentiment Analysis Conclusion  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/introduction/</guid>
      <description>The Final Fantasy series had an incredible effect on the gaming world. Developed by Square Enix and released for the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) in 1987, the game was considered an outlier at the time: games had simplistic plots and little to no character development. For this reason, the game was named &amp;ldquo;Final Fantasy,&amp;rdquo; for the game&amp;rsquo;s director thought it would be a failure for being a strange game at the time and would end his career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 - Dataset</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/dataset/</guid>
      <description>We analyzed two datasets for Final Fantasy XIV:
  The fan wiki of Final Fantasy XIV   The Final Fantasy XIV&amp;rsquo;s wiki was used to download all characters&#39; descriptions and attributes.
The data was extracted using the fandom wiki&amp;rsquo;s API and stored in JSON. Regular expressions were utilized to extract the description of each character along with the attributes of interest: race and affiliation. Other attributes were also extracted: gender, age, and occupation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 - Network</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/network/</guid>
      <description>The network created contains 385 nodes, each one related to character and 1472 edges. Firstly, we discarded the isolated nodes resulting in 335 remaining nodes. Afterwards, we extracted the Giant Component obtaining the final network which has 320 nodes and 1449 links.
        FFXIV (Undirected) Network    While there are significant hubs, the network is not dominated by a single entity. It is expected that in an online RPG, the protagonist is not as critical to the game&amp;rsquo;s plot development relative to single-player games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 - Text Analysis</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/analysis/</guid>
      <description>In order to perform the text analysis, we decided to prepare the data by applying tokenization and lemmatization to the character descriptions obtained from the wikipages. Words related to the structure of the wiki and not to a specific character of the story, where also removed from the text.
The frequency distribution of the 75 most common tokens is reported below. The frequency plot of the most common words is as expected: the two most common words are &amp;ldquo;final&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;fantasy,&amp;rdquo; followed by &amp;ldquo;warrior&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 - Finding Communities</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/community/</guid>
      <description>As we are interested in analyzing the relations amongst the characters, we want to try to detect communities and study their characteristics. In order to perform this analysis, we are going to apply the Louvain Algorithm for community detection to the undirected network created previously.
The algorithm detects 6 small communities that have less than 10 characters, and 8 bigger communities that have between 20 and 50 characters.
In the following plot the network is represented with a different color for every community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 - Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/sentiment/</guid>
      <description>We now proceed performing a sentiment analysis of the communities, after we gather the adequate text information related to the story of the characters.
We are going to perform different analyses. Firstly, we are going to use the LabMT dataset, to calculate the sentiment of each token, created from the textual description of the characters obtained from the wikipages, after proper tokenization and lemmatization. Subsequently, we are going to repeat the same process, this time using the text obtained from written dialogues extracted from the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 - Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Rasim-Deniz.github.io/final-fantasy-14/post/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>We analyzed Final Fantasy XIV&amp;rsquo;s character descriptions and dialogue in this project. After data extraction and preprocessing using the Final Fantasy Fandom Wiki&amp;rsquo;s API and regular expressions, a directed network was built and found to be behaving as a sparse, scaled-free network. The most linked characters met our expectations based on knowledge of the game, as they are central characters with a significant influence on the plot and the outcomes of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
